# OLEKSANDR BAILO

E:<u>alexandr.baylo@gmail.com</u> • M: (82)10-4943-1404 • Republic of Korea linkedin.com/in/abailo, https://github.com/BAILOOL

### **SUMMARY**

Currently enrolled in my last semester of the Master's degree, studying Machine Learning and Computer Vision. Experience in SLAM, stereo vision, object detection, visual question answering, emotion recognition.

**Programming Languages:** C/C++ • Python • MatLab • Java

Technical skills: Caffe • Tensorflow • Linux Bash • OpenCV • Git • Android Studio

Languages: Fluent in English, Russian and Ukrainian; Advanced level in Korean (TOPIK level 5/6)

### **EDUCATION**

### Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

Master of Science • Anticipated Graduation: August 2017

Department: Electrical Engineering • Robotics and Computer Vision (RCV) Laboratory supervised by In So Kweon

**Selected Publications:** 

Submitted Efficient Adaptive Non-Maximal Suppression Algorithms for Homogeneous Spatial Keypoint

to PRL Distribution

WACV17 Robust Road Marking Detection and Recognition Using Density-Based Grouping and ML Techniques

IPIU16 Area-Based Decision Driven Best-Buddies Similarity Method for Robust Template Matching

### Bachelor of Science • Graduation: August 2015

Department: Electrical Engineering & Business and Technology Management

Campus activities:

• Manager at KAIST International Basketball Club (KIBC).

• Vice President, Public Relations Head at KAIST International Student Association (KISA).

# Nanyang Technological University

Entrepreneurship & Innovation Asia Summer Program July – August 2014

# Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Spring Exchange Program February - May 2013

### **EXPERIENCE**

# K-Healthwear • Daejeon, South Korea • June 2015 – August 2015

### **Summer Intern**

- Developed an Android application for 12 lead ECG medical devices.
- Implemented real-time graphing functions of received data.

# My Design Lab • KAIST, South Korea • December 2014 – June 2015

### **Undergraduate Researcher**

- Devised "Automatized Wall Painting Drone" to implement painting works for the skyscrapers.
- Developed UAV control with Pixhawk, Mavlink Protocol and IronPython.

# Computer Vision and Image Processing Lab • KAIST, South Korea • December 2013 – June 2014 Undergraduate Researcher

- Developed an eye-friendly projector that prohibits a lighting beam from reaching the presenter's eyes.
- Software is available at <a href="http://cyclopsurp.weebly.com/">http://cyclopsurp.weebly.com/</a>.

### LAB PROJECTS

# Look Ahead by Shared Sensing for Cooperative Cars • September 2016 – Present

- Developing highly optimized multi-threaded modules of co-SLAM.
- Implementing algorithm to homogenously distribute points all over the image.

### Intelligent Assistant for People With Low Vision Abilities • December 2016 - Present

- Supervising two undergraduate students to implement mobile solution equipped with CV and ML algorithms.
- Researching and implementation of depth question answering.